Jan Horáček

Contact: jahor@jhr.cz / +420602603931

born 2.10.1979

LI https://www.linkedin.com/in/jahor/

GH jhrcz / TW @jhrcz



I'm strong believer in automation, testing, documentation and backups. For almost all my work I'm connected with all these main themes and trying to fill gaps I found in my work environment and inovate in these areas. Sharing my experience with coworkers is part of it.

After years, the most important skill I found is... thinking.

Work experience

Etnetera a.s.

- Senior linux administrator (2008 ...)
 - GitLab, Jenkins-CI, Kubernetes, RPM(deb) Packaging / testing, Nagios monitoring,
 Docker, Bacula, Ansible, CentOS (layout, kickstart, img), Dokuwiki, OpenNebula
 - Internal tools i do a lot of bash and ansible ;o)
 (lbstate, rctc (multi-instance tomcat controller), mkinstaller system installer initially
 GNU make and later Ansible based, Selenium grid API, system-reporter based on ansible runtime and elasticsearch data storage)
 - Azure / Google Cloud / AWS
 - OpenShift (2018-2019, Fortuna a.s., DevOPS Team)
 intial prometheus extractors, openshift object backuper, jenkins-ci
 - design and realization of infrastrucures for clients and maintenance
 (Kasa docker based & CI/CD, Logio dockerized devel infra & Gitlab-CI including deployment pipeline, SignatureSatori, and many other internal services)
- Team Leader Deployment and Operations (2008)
- Linux administrator (2004 2008)
 - FatWire CMS, Solaris, Sun Application Server / Access Manager
 - jNetPublish
 - design and realization of infrastrucures for clients and maintenance (O2, Annonce, Datart, MHMP, ...)

SOFTEX NCP

Web developer/network infrastructure technician (1997 - 2003)

PrgCont / Prague Container meetup

More active in the past, but still avid member and container and automation believer

Ansible workshop @ seznam.cz (2018)

Brought couple DevOps Meetups and Fedora release parties to our company.

OpenNebula

Brought OpenNebula VM managemet tool to our infrastructure and adopted LVM driver to suit our needs. With couple of other automation (Jenkins) and tooling its still in production.

- OpenNebula OSS LVM driver (2015)
- OpenNebula Conf 2014 Berlin Ligtning talk
- Opennebula Techday 2015 / Cesnet talk OpenNebula @ Etnetera

SUT

talk OpenNebula v praxi (2015) a talk Ansible best practices (2016)

InstallFest / LinuxDays / Fedora

- spíše "podporovatel" a pravidelný návštěvník
- · Fedora release parties Praha

I came to the IT and OpenSource community at Silliconhill. It was long time ago, but I still feel the connection with the community around SH, InstallFest and LinuxDays

Free time and hobbies

- RC Cars racing (Radio controlled cars, 1:8 / 1:10)
- Sport (Bike (even kickbike for some time), running, SNB, kitesurf, ...)

Certifications

All the certifications are not that important. Real inovation, learning new skills and tech and adopting to new technologies and tools is more important. Even more important is sharing knowledge with others. Still, in the past I got some cetifications:

- Architecting Microsoft Azure Solutions / 534, (2017, skončila platnost)
- Puppet a Foreman, (DataScript, 2016)
- RHCE / RHSA (id 111-088-852, 2011, not valid anymore)
- Solaris 10 Containers, resource management, zones (2007)

Education

- ZČU Plzeň / University of West Bohemia in Plzen 2003 2004 (unfinished)
- ČVUT FEL / Czech Technical University in Prague 1998 2003 (unfinished)
- SPŠ Chomutov 1994 - 1998

Languages

- **English** (without any ceritfication, average level, good enough to take part of conferences, read documentation and talk with someone about my work, experiences and hobbies)
- German (basics I have learnt at the school, but never had reason to practice it more)